Andrew Eisenberg collection of East African commercial sound recordings AD.MC.035
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Series I: Private collector (anonymous) - 78's, circa 1930-1965; 313 audio_recordings
  - Fundi Konde
    - Fundi Konde & His Guitar: Nilikisafiri, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 17.1 MB (Folder 86)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.437, J.R. 690. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:13.
    - Fundi Konde & His Guitar: Oh Mama Lady, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 17.2 MB (Folder 87)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.437, J.R. 688. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:15.
    - Fundi Konde & His Guitar: Ai Empologoloma, circa 1952; 1 audio_recording 19.0 MB (Folder 88)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.245, JR. 575. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:34.
    - Fundi Konde and His Guitar: Mapenzi Ya Kwetu Sisi, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 89)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.245, J.R. 574. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:53.
    - Fundi Konde & His Guitar: Mapenzi Nikipofu, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 16.6 MB (Folder 90)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.484, J.R. 996. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:08.
    - Fundi Konde & His Guitar: Mombasa Hakuna Kazi, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 16.3 MB (Folder 91)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.484, J.R. 997. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:05.
    - Fundi Konde & His Guitar: Jike Na Dume Kongwe, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 16.3 MB (Folder 92)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.485, J.R. 1006. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:04.
    - Fundi Konde & His Guitar: Kwa Heri Mpenzi Wangu, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 17.0 MB (Folder 93)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.485, J.R. 1007. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:12.
    - Fundi Konde: Hao Hao Ndiyo, N/A; 1 audio_recording 16.4 MB (Folder 94)
      Serial number: Troubadour, AFC.182, 1306. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:06.
    - Fundi Konde: Simba, 1 audio_recording (Folder 95)
      Serial number: Troubadour, AFC.182, 1307. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:40.
    - Fundi Konde: Elina Ni Wako, 1 audio_recording 13.9 MB (Folder 96)
      Serial number: Troubadour, BZ.1248, AD 554, BZ.1248. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:37.
    - Fundi Konde: Jana Naliota Ndoto, 1 audio_recording 14.3 MB (Folder 97)
      Serial number: Troubadour, BZ.1248, AD 553. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:42.
  - Home Boys Band
    - Home Boys Band: Duwa Njema Kwa Manani, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 13.1 MB (Folder 98)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.524, J.R. 1090. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:28.
    - Home Boys Band: Mpenzi Siku Zote Nambia, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 13.5 MB (Folder 99)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.524, J.R. 1091, EA.524. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:32.
  - Idi bin Salim
    - Idi Bin Salim: Mafindsu ya Mume, N/A; 1 audio_recording 15.6 MB (Folder 100)
      Physical characteristic of original
      Serial number: Tazama, TM 484, IS.1. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:56.
    - Idi Bin Salim: Wanawake Use Tange, 1 audio_recording 15.6 MB (Folder 101)
      Serial number: Tazama, TM 485, IS.1. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:56.
  - Jambo Boys
    - Jambo Boys: Ngongo Twaingia, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 13.9 MB (Folder 102)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.824, J.R. 1640. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Artists: Fadhili Williams (guitar), Mohammed (double bass), Harrison (drums), Ismael Mumba (trumpet). Duration: 2:37.
    - Jambo Boys: Shimba Mbawi, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 13.3 MB (Folder 103)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.824, J.R. 1641. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Artists: Fadhili Williams (guitar), Mohammed (double bass), Harrison (drums), Ismael Mumba (trumpet). Duration: 2:30.
  - Jauharah Orchestra
    - Jauharah Orchestra: Siwezi Taabu, 1950; 1 audio_recording 12.3 MB (Folder 104)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.2229, ABC.13678. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Leader: Shariff T. Twahir. Duration: 2:19.
    - Jauharah Orchestra: Wakilindaje Kisima?, 1950; 1 audio_recording 15.9 MB (Folder 105)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.2229, ABC.13676. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Leader: Shariff T. Twahir. Duration: 3:10.
    - Jauharah Orchestra: Damu Imenikauka - Side B, 1950; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 106)
      Serial number: Trek, DC.426, XYZ.7239. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Artists: Leader: Sheriff Twahir Ahmed; Singer: Singer: Mbarak Rashid. Duration: 2:59.
    - Jauharah Orchestra: Mimi, circa 1950-1953; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 107)
      Serial number: Trek, DC.426, XYZ.7238. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Artists: Leader: Sheriff Twahir Ahmed; Singer: Hussein Khamis. Duration: 2:50.
  - Joseph Nazareth & the Calypso Kids
    - Joseph Nazareth & The Calypso Kids: Mji Mombasa, 1 audio_recording 15.2 MB (Folder 108)
      Serial number: Gallotone, OK.511, ABC/EA.17039. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:52.
  - Jumaine Omari
    - Jumaine Omari & Party: Na Safari, circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 14.9 MB (Folder 109)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.65, A.B. 130. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:48.
      Mzuri
    - Jumaine Omari & Party: Tu Tai Wacha Dunia, circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 14.6 MB (Folder 110)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.65, A.B.129. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Title should read: "Tutaiwacha Dunia." Duration: 2:45.
  - Jumbe Ali
    - Jumbe Ali: Mpenzi Waniumiza, N/A; 1 audio_recording 18.7 MB (Folder 111)
      Serial number: HMV, MA.118, OAF. 151. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:32.
    - Jumbe Ali: Kheri Kunitinda, N/A; 1 audio_recording 16.8 MB (Folder 112)
      Serial number: HMV, MA.120, OAF 155. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:10.
    - Jumbe Ali: Siiwezi Tabu, N/A; 1 audio_recording 18.9 MB (Folder 113)
      Serial number: HMV, MA.120, OAF.156. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:34.
  - Kasanga and Party
    - Kasanga & Party: Paka Cheza Rumba Part I, N/A; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 114)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.15, CES.10023. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:50.
    - Kasanga & Party: Paka Cheza Rumba Part II, N/A; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 115)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.15, CES.10024. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:53.
  - Kibokoni Dramatic Party
    - Kibokoni Dramatic Party: Yamini Nakuapia, 1 audio_recording 18.4 MB (Folder 116)
      Serial number: HMV, MA.118, OAF.152. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:28.
  - Kibwana and Party
    - Kibwana & Party of Charlsea Club: Nalila Hilati, 1 audio_recording 14.1 MB (Folder 117)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2132, CES 4023. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:40.
    - Kibwana & Party: Kweli, 1 audio_recording 18.4 MB (Folder 118)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2172, CES.1319. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:28.
    - Kibwana and Party: Jawabu ya Mtama, 1 audio_recording 16.7 MB (Folder 119)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2201, CES.135. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:08.
    - Kibwana and Party: Sija Furahika, 1 audio_recording 16.3 MB (Folder 120)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2201, CES.1352. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:04.
    - Kibwana Orchestra: Kula Mara, 1 audio_recording 15.7 MB (Folder 121)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.438, MOM. 50. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:58.
    - Kibwana Orchestra: Mdomo Wake Sukari, 1 audio_recording 17.7 MB (Folder 122)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.438, MOM. 51. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:20.
  - King's African Rifles
    - The King's African Rifles: (1) Hiyani! Hiyani! (2) Simba Mkali, N/A; 1 audio_recording 15.6 MB (Folder 123)
      Serial number: Columbia, GE.17805, CEI.23853. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:57.
    - The King's African Rifles: (1) Mungu Amweke Colonel Weru (2) Ngoma ya Malini (3) Mtota Nalilia Mama!, 1 audio_recording 17.5 MB (Folder 124)
      Serial number: Columbia, GE.17805, CEI.23854. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:18.
    - (King's African Rifles) Askari wa 2nd King's African Rifles: Kodi Modaiwona Konde Ya Wazungu, circa 1930; 1 audio_recording 14.6 MB (Folder 125)
      Serial numbers: Columbia, WE.36, W.63460. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:45.
    - (King's African Rifles) Askari wa 6th King's African Rifles: Ininzatani Pasiko Nakunalisa, circa 1930; 1 audio_recording 12.9 MB (Folder 126)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.36, W.63456. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:25.
  - Lamu Omari
    - Lamu Omari: Muganga, circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 15.5 MB (Folder 127)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.427, AB. 854. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:55.
    - Lamu Omari: Waume Watele, circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording (Folder 128)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.427, AB. 853. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:01.
    - Lamu Omari: Boi, circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 15.5 MB (Folder 129)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.430, AB. 859. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:55.
    - Lamu Omari: Fondo Goa, circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 14.3 MB (Folder 130)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.430, AB. 860. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:42.
  - Landova Lele-Mama
    - Landova Lele-Mama Band: Meja Khatibu, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 16.7 MB (Folder 131)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.274, JR.649. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:09.
    - Landova Lele-Mama Band: Nirauni, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 16.8 MB (Folder 132)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.274, JR.648,. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:10.
  - Lulu Orchestra
    - Lulu Orchestra and Star: Bahati Ya Masikini, N/A; 1 audio_recording 16.2 MB (Folder 133)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.38, CES.10090. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:03.
    - Lulu Orchestra and Star: Dunia Imebadilika, N/A; 1 audio_recording 15.7 MB (Folder 134)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.38, CES.10089. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:57.
    - Lulu Orchestra and Star: Mahabani Tamu, N/A; 1 audio_recording 14.0 MB (Folder 135)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.39, CES.10092. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes from label: Artist: Muhimu Baluchi; Composer: Star Orchestra. Duration: 2:38.
    - Lulu Orchestra and Star: Nimeswalitika, N/A; 1 audio_recording 15.6 MB (Folder 136)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.39, CES.10091, EOM.39. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes from label: Artist: Usu; Composer: Star Orchestra. Duration: 2:56.
    - Lulu Orchestra & Vocal: Kila, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 15.5 MB (Folder 137)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.803, J.R. 1600. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:55.
    - Lulu Orchestra & Vocal: Nilivyo Dho Fika, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 14.9 MB (Folder 138)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.803, J.R. 1599. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:48.
    - Lulu Orchestra / Huseni & Siti Wewe: Mtaka Mawili, circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 15.5 MB (Folder 139)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.12, AB 24. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:56.
    - Lulu Orchestra / Huseni & Party: Naapa Kupenda, circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 14.8 MB (Folder 140)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.12, AB 23. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:48.
    - Lulu Orchestra / Husseini & Siti Masika & Party: Bui Kweli, circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 15.1 MB (Folder 141)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc Serial number: Mzuri, AM.29, AB 57. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Artists: Siti Masika Sulemani, Husseini. Duration: 2:50.
    - Lulu Orchestra / Husseini & Siti Masika & Party: Juba, circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 142)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.29, AB 58. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Artists: Siti Masika Sulemani, Husseini. Duration: 2:49.
    - Lulu & Sulemani Orchestra / Siti Masika Sulemani & Party: "Kicheko", circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 16.9 MB (Folder 143)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.32, AB 64,. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:20.
    - Lulu & Sulemani Orchestra / Siti Masika Sulemani & Party: "Nikilala", circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 16.9 MB (Folder 144)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.32, AB 63. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:11.
  - Maalim Abdi
    - Maalimabdi: Miswi—Baha, Part 1, N/A; 1 audio_recording 16.1 MB (Folder 145)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.257, CES.530. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:02.
    - Maalimabdi: Miswi—Baha, Part 2, N/A; 1 audio_recording 15.1 MB (Folder 146)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.257, CES.531, EO.257. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:51.
    - Maalim Abdi: "Moyo Nalikuzuiya" Part 1, 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 147)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2109, CES 966. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:58.
    - Maalim Abdi: "Moyo Nalikuzuiya" Part 2, 1 audio_recording 16.2 MB (Folder 148)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2109, CES 967. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:03.
    - Maalim Abdi: "Uso Wa Rupia" Part 2., N/A; 1 audio_recording 15.6 MB (Folder 149)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2110, CES 973. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:56.
    - Maalim Abdi: "Uso Wa Rupia" Part I., N/A; 1 audio_recording 16.1 MB (Folder 150)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2110, CES 972. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:02.
    - Maalim Abdi: "Umenishangaza"—Part I, N/A; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 151)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2123, CES.974. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:58.
    - Maalim Abdi: "Umenishangaza"—Part II, N/A; 1 audio_recording 16.5 MB (Folder 152)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2123, CES.975. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:06.
  - Malim Shaban
    - Malim Shaban: Uniombee Karima—Sehemu Ya Kwanza, circa 1930; 1 audio_recording 17.1 MB (Folder 153)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.21, W 63124. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan Duration: 3:13.
    - Malim Shaban: Uniombee Karima—Sehemu Ya Pili, circa 1930; 1 audio_recording 16.8 MB (Folder 154)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.21, W 63123. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan. Duration: 3:10.
    - Malim Shaban: Hadithi ya Bibi na Vijakazi Part 1, circa 1930; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 155)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.54, W.63185. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan. Duration: 2:46.
    - Malim Shaban: Hadithi ya Bibi na Vijakazi Part 2, circa 1930; 1 audio_recording 14.8 MB (Folder 156)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.54, W.63186. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan. Duration: 2:29.
  - Mashairi
    - Mashairi / Kaluta Amri Rin Abedi: Dawa mziwanda kula, kula upate afia, 1950; 1 audio_recording 14.2 MB (Folder 157)
      Serial: Gallotone, GB.1265, XYZ.5114, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:41.
    - Mashairi / Saadini Abdo Kandoro: Sili nisichotamani sili ingawa ni dawa, N/A; 1 audio_recording 11.5 MB (Folder 158)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1265, XYZ.5113, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:10.
  - Maulidi
    - Maulidi: Nimekwenda Shela, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 17.9 MB (Folder 159)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.131, JR. 234. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:23.
    - Maulidi: Ugeni Mbaya, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 18.4 MB (Folder 160)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.131, JR. 235. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:28.
  - Mohamed Ali Badi
    - Mohamedali Badi:Ma Bwana Wa K.A.R., 1 audio_recording 18.4 MB (Folder 161)
      Serial number: HMV, MA.13, OAF.26. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Mohamedali Badi, Mohamed Ali Badi, Mohamed Badi. Duration: 3:28.
    - Mohamed Ali Badi & Party: Siku Ku Khalifu, circa 1938-1946; 1 audio_recording 17.5 MB (Folder 162)
      Serial number: HMV, MA.40, OAF 79. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Mohamedali Badi, Mohamed Ali Badi, Mohamed Badi. Title should read: "Sikukuu Khalifu." Duration: 3:18.
    - Mohamed Ali Badi & Party: Sitokushutumu, circa 1938-1946; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 163)
      Serial number: HMV, MA.40, OAF 80. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Mohammed Ali Badi, Mohamed Ali Badi, Mohamed Badi. Duration: 2:59
    - Mohamed Ali Badi & His Orchestra: Kheti Mukijuwa, 1938-1946; 1 audio_recording 16.7MB (Folder 164)
      Serial number: HMV, MA.41, OAF.81. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other note: Singer also known as: Mohammed Ali Badi, Mohamed Ali Badi, Mohamed Badi. Duration: 3:09.
    - Mohamed Ali Badi & His Orchestra: Umenidhalili, circa 1938-1946; 1 audio_recording 16.5 MB (Folder 165)
      Serial number: HMV, MA.41, OAF.82. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Mohamedali Badi, Mohamed Ali Badi, Mohamed Badi. Duration: 3:06.
  - Mohamed Ali Bwagajuga
    - Mohamed Ali Bwagajuga: Pole, mama Kitwana, 1950; 1 audio_recording 12.9 MB (Folder 166)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1261, XYZ.6085, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:26.
    - Mohomedi A. Bwagajuga: Ukiwa wangu, 1950; 1 audio_recording 14.4 MB (Folder 167)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1261, XYZ.6092, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:42.
    - Mohomedi A. Bwagajuga: Dar es Salaam usiende, circa 1950; 1 audio_recording 12.9 MB (Folder 168)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1262, XYZ.6093, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:26.
    - Mohomedi A. Bwagajuga: Nimepiga pegi mbili, tatu, circa 1950; 1 audio_recording 13.6 MB (Folder 169)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1262, XYZ.6091, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:34.
    - M. A. Bwagajuga: Nimechoka kusubiri, N/A; 1 audio_recording 13.0 MB (Folder 170)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1572, XYZ.6086, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:37.
    - Mohamed Ali Bwagajuga: Kipenzi Changu, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 13.4 MB (Folder 171)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.527, J.R. 1097. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:31.
    - Mohamed Ali Bwagajuga: Nimechoka Kusubiri, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 13.9 MB (Folder 172)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.527, J.R. 1096, EA.527. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:27.
    - Mohamed Ali Bwagajuga: Nani Wakuchela, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording (Folder 173)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.528, J.R. 1099. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:31.
    - Mohamed Ali Bwagajuga: Oh Buchwala, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 13.9 MB (Folder 174)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.528, J.R. 1098. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:37.
  - Morning Star Orchestra
    - Morning Star Orchestra: Mcheza Kwao Hutuzwa, circa 1956-1959; 1 audio_recording 14.8 MB (Folder 175)
      Serial number: Tom Tom, TR.454. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Vocalist, Mohammed Athman. Duration: 2:47.
    - Morning Star Orchestra: Star Waltz, circa 1956-1959; 1 audio_recording 15.4 MB (Folder 176)
      Serial number: Tom Tom, TR.454, T 0770. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Vocalist, Shafi Athman. Duration: 2:54.
  - Morogoro Jazz Band
    - Morogoro Jazz Band: Nitumie Dawa, N/A; 1 audio_recording 13.7 MB (Folder 177)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.69, OAM.168. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Leader: Makara Kindemire. Duration: 2:35
    - Morogoro Jazz Band: Tupendane Kwa Mapenzi, N/A; 1 audio_recording 13.5 MB (Folder 178)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.69, OAM.170. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Leader: Makara Kindemire. Duration: 2:33.
    - Morogoro Jazz Band: Mengi Masikitiko, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 179)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.558, J.R. 1159. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:47.
    - Morogoro Jazz Band: Vya Kumpyelo, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 15.4 MB (Folder 180)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.558, J.R. 1158. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:55.
    - Morogoro Jazz Band: Wapinga Wose Wanileka, circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 15.2 MB (Folder 181)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.199, AB 397, TA.1242. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:51.
    - Morogoro Jazz Band: Ye Baa, circa 1955-1965; 1 audio_recording 15.4 MB (Folder 182)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.199, AB 398, TA.1242. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:55.
  - Musa Maruf
    - Musa Maruf: Diamond Jubilee, N/A; 1 audio_recording 17.8 MB (Folder 183)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.203, J.R. 219. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:22.
    - Musa Maruf: Tororo, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 15.6 MB (Folder 184)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.203, J.R. 220. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:57.
    - Musa Maruf: Kala Shahiri, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 18.9 MB (Folder 185)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.262, JR.539. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:34.
    - Musa Maruf: Kama-Hutaki-Mambia, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 19.2 MB (Folder 186)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.262, JR.538. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:38.
    - Musa Maruf: Katika Duniya, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 17.3 MB (Folder 187)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.421, J.R. 772. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:16.
    - Musa Maruf: Mpenzi Wangu Kanitoka, circa 1952-1961; 1 audio_recording 17.4 MB (Folder 188)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.421, J.R. 773. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:17.
  - Ngoma ya Kilua
    - Ngoma ya Kilua: Tata Kibondo, circa 1930; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 189)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.38, W 63266. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:46.
  - Nyameshe Kitoto Adel
    - Nyameshe Kitoto Adel: Bibi Sofia, N/A; 1 audio_recording 14.0 MB (Folder 190)
      Serial number: Arrow, ARC.508, ZD. 15. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:38.
    - Nyameshe Kitoto Adel: Ulevi Kubaya, N/A; 1 audio_recording 14.0 MB (Folder 191)
      Serial number: Arrow, ARC.508, ZD.16. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:39.
  - Nyamwezi Women
    - Nyamwezi Women with Lugobe: Kwa Mungu kunyenyekea, N/A; 1 audio_recording 13.7 MB (Folder 192)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1311, XYZ.5099, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:35.
    - Nyamwezi Women with Masudi Bini Amani: Mtemi mfalume wize mpya, N/A; 1 audio_recording 14.5 MB (Folder 193)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1311, XYZ.5098, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:44.
  - Omar and Party of Charlsea [sic] Club
    - Omar & Party of Charlsea Club: Wata Ninyamae, N/A; 1 audio_recording (Folder 194)